Hello friends, we are going to compare the quarter 4 numbers of two big private sector
banks, HDFC Bank and ICICI Bank.
We will cover all the numbers in detail
and find out
which bank we see emerging as the winner in this ongoing fight between the two banks in the
future.  We will also discuss what
their asset quality has
been and which bank is
proving better numbers in asset quality.  There is a
lot of such data in the video
which we are going to cover.  First of all
we will talk about market cap.
After that in the video we will know about the
deposits and advances i.e. loans of both the banks.  We
will also look at the net interest income numbers and at the same time we are also going to talk about names.
We will look at the profit numbers to see
which bank is
making more profit.  If we talk about CASA ratio
and cost to income ratio,
we are also going to cover these numbers.
We will also cover asset quality.
We are also going to cover dividends and dividend payout ratio in the video.
After that, in the last you will see that
we are also going to talk about the branch network of both the banks.
So friends let's start the video
and talk about market cap.
See, if you look at it according to the market cap, then
here
we see HDFC Bank as the winner.
We are seeing a market cap of Rs 14,85,854 crore.
If we talk about ICI Bank,
you will see that
here
we are seeing the market cap of ICI Bank of Rs 10,31,369 crore.  So
here if we talk about the winner, then
HDFC Bank
seems to be becoming the winner according to the market cap.  Let's move ahead
and now we will talk about deposits.
If you look at the deposit numbers,
in the case of HDFC, you will see that
whatever numbers have been taken in this video during the Q4 numbers have been
taken as per the numbers till Q4 FI25.
So if you look at the case of HDFC,
we have seen its deposits of around Rs 2528000 crore.
If we talk about ICICI Bank, then if
you look at the deposits here,
we will see deposits worth Rs 1610348 crore.
So, if we look at the deposit number,
here also the winner we see
is HDFC Bank.  Let's continue with the
video
and further we will talk about loans i.e. advances.
So if you see here,
HDFC Bank has
given a total loan of Rs 269500 ​​crore to its customers.  If we
look at the number of ICI Bank,
we get the number of Rs 1341766 crore.
If we talk about the winner here, then
here also we can see HDFC Bank in the
lead.  Let's move ahead
in the video and now we will talk about net
interest income.  The core earning of any bank is
net interest
income.  Banks earn most of their money through interest.
Now
if you look at the case of HDFC, when the latest Q4
numbers came,
they had a net interest income of around Rs 32,000 crore.
If we talk about ICI Bank, then
we saw the net interest income
of ICI Bank which is Rs 21193 crore.  If
you compare through net interest income, then
HDFC Bank is seen as the winner here.
But if we talk
about net interest margin, then you will see that
we have seen a net interest margin of 3.54%
for HDFC Bank and if you look at the numbers of ICI Bank, then
we have seen a net interest margin of 4.41%.
That is, if you compare under the net interest margin, then
here you can see ICI Bank as the
winner.   Let's move
ahead in the video and now we will talk about
profit.  If
you look at the profit numbers, HDFC Bank had made a profit of Rs 17,620 crore
during Q4.
If you look at the profit of ICICI Bank,
we have seen a profit of Rs 12,630 crore.  That
is, if you look at the profit numbers,
HDFC Bank appears to be the winner.  We will continue
in the video.  Now we are going to talk
about CASA ratio and cost to income ratio.
Look, if we talk about Kasai ratio,
here you will see the ratio of HDFC Bank which is
around 35%.
If we talk about ICI Bank, then
here you can see ICI Bank becoming the winner,
we have seen 38.4% CASA ratio.  That
means, according to the CASA ratio,
you will see ICI Bank in the future.
If we talk about the cost to income ratio, then
here
HDFC Bank has 39.8% and if
you see ICI Bank,
we have seen 37.9%.
If you compare the cost to income ratio of ICI Bank, then
here you will see that ICI Bank is
better.  That is, if
we compare this, then
ICI Bank is the winner here.   Let's move
ahead.  Now let's talk about asset
quality.  If you look at the numbers of HDFC Bank in asset quality,
we have seen the gross NPA ratio at 1.3%.
If we look at ICI Bank, we have seen 1.67% here.
After that,
if we cover the number of net NPA, then
almost similar numbers of both the banks are seen.
But if we compare on the basis of net NPA, then
we have found ICI Bank to be better
and
if you look on the basis of gross NPA, then here
we are finding HDFC Bank to be better.
Next we will talk about dividend and
dividend payout ratio.  So,
if you
talk about dividend during the latest quarter, then the dividend on
equity of ₹22 has been announced by HDFC Bank.
If we talk about ICICI Bank, then the
dividend was announced by ICI Bank on the share at ₹11.  Now
if we talk about dividend payout ratio, then
here HDFC Bank is
seen to be higher.  24% is his own,
whatever his earnings were during the entire financial year,
he has given 24% of that to
his investors as dividend.
But if we talk about ICICI Bank, then
here you will find the payout ratio
quite low.  That means if you
look here, HDFC Bank has been found
to be the winner.  If we talk about branch network now,
if you look at the branch network in the end, then here also you will
see that the winner is HDFC Bank.
We saw 9455 branches during the latest quarter of the bank.
If we talk about ICICI Bank,
we have seen 6983 branches.  So if
you look here,
we see HDFC Bank as the winner here also.  And
in the last, we would like to make a request to you that
if you liked the video then
like the video and
if I have been able to give you 1 or 2% information through the video then
friends, please keep subscribing to the channel.
Thank you very much for your valuable time.